Hello! My name is Rogério Fernando Machado, and I’m from Sapucaia do Sul , Brazil. I’m 53 years old, and I’m currently studying Systems Development. In my free time, I enjoy coding, reading tech blogs, playing chess, and working on DIY electronics.
I chose Information Technology because I’ve always been passionate about technology and solving problems. For me, IT is a field where I can be creative, build useful tools, and learn something new every day.
I work with different programming languages like JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, HTML and CSS, and also COBOL for legacy systems.
Some tools I often use are VS Code, Eclipse, NetBeans, Git, GitHub, MySQL, SQLite, and I also have basic knowledge of React and Figma.
I also value my soft skills, such as teamwork, communication, problem-solving, and time management.
One of my favorite projects is called Ferragem na Mão, which means 'Hardware in Hand' in Portuguese. It’s a web system that helps small hardware stores manage their inventory and sales digitally.
I built it using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and LocalStorage. It’s responsive and includes features like dark mode and product registration.
In the future, I want to work as a Front-End or Full-Stack Developer. I admire companies like Google and Nubank, and startups that focus on education and sustainability.
My learning goals include improving my English, learning React and Angular deeply, and getting certified in cloud technologies like AWS or Azure.
Thank you for watching my video! If you’d like to know more about me or my projects, feel free to get in touch. Bye!